Abner Dean papers ML-44
Rauner Special Collections Library
Abner Dean papers
1926-1981
Rauner Special Collections Library
Dean, Abner
ML-44
60 linear ft. 40 boxes
Abner Dean (1910-1982), cartoonist. Dartmouth College Class of 1931. Consist of sketches, plaster and wooden sculptures, advertising layouts, printed illustrations,pamphlets, programs, book jackets, newspapers and newspaper clippings relating to his career as a cartoonist, commercial artist and inventor. Copies of articles, book jackets and manuscripts with his illustrations are also included.
Scope and Contents
The papers of Abner Dean contain manuscripts, advertisements, artwork including sketches, wooden and plaster sculptures, painted wooden buttons and paintings, illustrations of books, book jackets, magazines and articles, photographs, programs, clippings, pamphlets, newspapers and cartoons, as well as examples of his work with the Printer's Devil Press and a 35 mm film entitled "Too True To Be good". The materials detail his prolific work as a cartoonist, commercial artist, sculptor and inventor.
Conditions Governing Access
Unrestricted.
Dean, Abner
Biography
Abner Dean was born on March 18, 1910, in New York City. He attended the National Academy of Art in 1927, before entering Dartmouth College from which he graduated in 1931. Dean's artistic career began during his undergraduate years at Dartmouth when he was the first sophomore ever to be elected art editor of the "Jack-O-Lantern" and he won first prize in "College Humor Magazine's" National College Comic Artist competition. He also founded Printer's Devil Press with Frank B. Cornell while still as student in 1930. After graduation, he became a freelance artist and his cartoons began appearing in "Esquire," "Collier's," "The New Yorker," and "Life" magazines. His first book of cartoons "It's A Long Way To Heaven" was published in 1945, followed by "What Am I doing Here" in 1945 and "On The Eighth Day" in 1949. In the 1970's Dean invented an industrial building system assembly and a multilevel folding table. Abner Dean died on June 30, 1982 in New York City.
- Addendum 2, undated; 3
  Scope and Contents
  Contains plaster and wood sculptures
  - Contains one painted plaster sculpture; two wooden sculptures; painted wooden buttons; 35 mm fil..., undated (Box 34)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Unrestricted
    Contains one painted plaster sculpture; two wooden sculptures; painted wooden buttons; 35 mm film "To True To Be Good"
  - Contains one plaster sculpture, undated (Box 35)
    Contains one plaster sculpture
  - Contains two painted plaster sculptures; one wooden sculpture; framed photo of plaster sculpture..., undated (Box 36)
    Contains two painted plaster sculptures; one wooden sculpture; framed photo of plaster sculpture (seal balancing ball)
  - Contains one painted plaster sculpture; two wooden sculptures, undated (Box 37)
    Contains one painted plaster sculpture; two wooden sculptures
  - Contains three painted plaster sculptures, undated (Box 38)
    Contains three painted plaster sculptures
  - Contains two wooden sculptures; one painted plaster sculpture, undated (Box 39)
    Contains two wooden sculptures; one painted plaster sculpture
  - Contains three painted plaster sculptures, undated (Box 40)
- Papers, 1926-1981; 1
  Unrestricted.
  Manuscripts, magazines, advertisements, book jackets and newspaper articles featuring Dean cartoons, as well as paintings, clippings, programs, pamphlets, prints, photographs and sketches.
  - Magazines - Sketches, 1933-1981 (Box 5)
    Magazines - Sketches
    - Magazines: "New York"; June 11, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Magazines: "The New Yorker", 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Magazines: "24"; March, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Magazines: "United Methodists Today"; December, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Magazines: "Way Out"; June, July, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous general, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Multilevel folding table: Construction notes and sketches, 1966-1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Multilevel folding table: Drawings of the completed table, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Multilevel folding table: Metal plaque, reading: Abner Dean Multilevel Folding Table, Patent No. 3,387,573, Wood Products Division, ILC, Hermon, New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Multilevel folding table: Plans showing measurements of individual pieces of the table, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Negative photocopies of a series of grammar lessons, illustrated by Abner Dean; source unidentified, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Newsletters: "Greenmarket News"; October, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Newsletters: "Printer's Ink"; November 15, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Thirty-One Up"; March 26, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1932-1964 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Obituary, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Paintings: Country house scenes, interior and exterior, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Watercolor of a caged tiger, by Paul Malo, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Newspaper: "The Dartmouth"; February 12, 1938, Photo Gravure Edition, February 12 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Pamphlets: G. I. Movies, prepared by Army Services Forces, U.S. Army, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Pamphlets: Salon of American Humorists, A Political and Social Pageant From the Revolution to the Present Day, assembled by the College Art Association, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Pamphlets: Simon and Schuster Publications 1924-1957, 1924-1958, by Simon and Schuster, Inc., 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Photographs: Abner Dean, illustrating models of his building system, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Photographs: Building System Model, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Photographs: Folding table, undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Photographs: Negatives and contact sheets, for the prints of the folding table, building system and sculptures created by Dean, undated (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Photographs: Sculptures by Abner Dean, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Prints: Albertina Facsimile prints of works by Michelangelo and Leonardo Da Vinci, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Prints: Angry angels and devils, probably done in felt-tipped pen, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Prints: Bird flying alone, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Prints: Bowl of fruit, with a worm, probably done in felt-tipped pen, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Prints: Man and woman juggling eggs, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Prints: Peasant scene and a postcard of Rembrandt's "Flora;" prints by Max Jaffe, Vienna, published by the Metropolitan Museum of Art, New York, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Prints: Two birds strangling each other, undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Professional signatures, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - Programs: "American Cartooning"; Metropolitan Museum of Art, May 11-June 10, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Programs: "An Exhibit of American Cartoons"; presented by Letters Abroad at the Sheraton East, April 6, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Programs: "The Fourth Annual American Dance Festival"; Connecticut College, New London, August 16-19, 1951 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Sketches: Artist at work, crayon, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Sketches: Child: "Liza;" October 30, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Sketches: Clown, in watercolor, by John Rose, undated (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Sketches: Dogs, undated (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Sketches: Faces, cartoon and caricature, undated (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Sketches: Female nudes, in exaggerated poses; watercolor, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Sketches: Humorous sketches of country life, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Sketches: Ideas for book jackets; watercolor, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Sketches: Logo for the Dartmouth College Class of 1931 50th Reunion, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Sketches: Man and woman in various poses; pen and ink, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Sketches: Miscellaneous, 1933-1955 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Sketches: Pen and ink sketches of a woman dancing with, or attacked by, birds, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Sketches: Two sketches by Bernard Sanders, undated (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Book Mss: "Wake Me When It's Over" - Cartoons, 1934-1968 (Box 2)
    Book Mss: "Wake Me When It's Over" - Cartoons
    - Book Mss:"Wake Me When It's Over"; manuscript and layout in codex form, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Book Mss: "Wake Me When It's Over"; verses, carbon copy, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Book Mss:"What Am I Doing Here?"; notebook containing Dean's analyses of cartoons used in the book, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Book Mss:"What Am I Doing Here?"; pages from the book I, incomplete, undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Book Mss:"What Am I Doing Here?"; pages from the book II, incomplete, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Building system; Number of pieces of material in section of the building model, sizes, and thickness measurements, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Cards made from Dean's cartoons; created by "Bernad," Yonkers, New York, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Caricatures and sketched portraits of Abner Dean9, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Caricatures, misc., undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons: Black and white sketches for "Johnson and Johnson Magazine", undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons:Black and white sketches for the "New York Times Magazine," primarily political and American scene cartoons, I, undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Cartoons:Black and white sketches for the "New York Times Magazine," primarily political and American scene cartoons, II, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Cartoons:Black and white sketches for the "New York Times Magazine," primarily political and American scene cartoons, III, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Cartoons: Colored sketches for "American Cyanamid Magazine", undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons: Cover design for "American Legion Magazine", undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Cartoons: Editorial cartoons, drawn for API, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Cartoons: Elf bartender, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons: Intended for publication in the "American Journal of Nursing", undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Cartoons: Large woman and tiny man in series of sketches, 1934 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cartoons:Men in various poses and attitudes, undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Cartoons: Notebook of rough watercolor sketches, some later used in Dean's books, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Cartoons: Published work in "Collier's Magazine", undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Cartoons: Published work in "Medical World News", undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Cartoons: Published work in "Medical World News," with transparencies, undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Cartoons: Published work in The New Yorker; January 2, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Cartoons: Rough and finished drawings from a "Pageant" article on verbal communication, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Cartoons: Rough drawings considered for use in Dean's books I, undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Cartoons - Illustrations, 1929-1975 (Box 3)
    Cartoons - Illustrations
    - Cartoons: Rough drawings considered for use in Dean's books II, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons: Schmoo-like figures, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons:Series: "Fallen Angel", 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons: Series: "One Damn Foot After Another"; published copy, source unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons: Series: "One Damn Foot After Another"; rough drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons: Series:" Poker Players", undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons: Series:"TV Viewers"; rough and finished sketches, undated (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons: Series: Untitled, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons: Series:"Waking Up", undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons: Series: Watercolor or color wash background sketches for the" Elks Magazine", undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1940-1945 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Christmas card designed for Walter P. Chrysler, Jr., undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Crossword puzzles, undated (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Dartmouth College: Advertisments, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Dartmouth College: Covers for programs of events in Hanover and at the College, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Dartmouth College: Football program covers, 1929-1930 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Dartmouth College: Greeting Cards, undated (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Dartmouth College: Illustrations for the "Arts Quarterly," June, 1931 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Dartmouth College: Magazine cover: "Psi Epsilog", undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Dartmouth College: Magazine and program logos, undated (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Dartmouth College: Miscellaneous, undated (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Ethel Dean: Pen and ink sketch of a flower arrangement, undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Amanda," by Bob Elliott and Ray Goulding; in "Collier's" Magazine, January 26, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Ambitious Mothers: Hollywood Headache," by Arthur Marx; in "Collier's" Magazine, August 2, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "America's Smart Set," by Jhan and June Robbins; in "This Week," June 25, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Breaking Through the Medications Mystique," by Myra E. Levine; in "American Journal of Nursing," April, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Cannibals in the Capitol," by Scott W. Lucas; in "This Week," June 27, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Clinical and Administrative Judgment," by Marjorie Ramphal; in "American Journal of Nursing," September, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Colloquy in Wisconsin," by Sargent Armstrong; in "Stage", undated (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Illustrations: Articles:"Confessions of a Television Writer," by William Fay; in "Elks" Magazine, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Cult of Culture," by Elaine Kendall; in "Show Magazine," March, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Democracy By Dissent," by Erie Stanley Gardner; in "This Week," October 2, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Doctor-Nurse Game," by Leonard I. Stein; in "American Journal of Nursing," January, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Doctor-Nurse Teamwork," author unidentified; in "American Journal of Nursing," October, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Do You Really Play Golf?," by Joseph C. Dey, Jr.; in "Collier's" Magazine, July 8, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Exercise and Live Better," by Robert Froman; in "Elks Magazine", undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Expert Finds Legal Threat in Formulary System," author unidentified; in "Medical World News," September 17, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Failure of Marxism," by John Dos Passos; in "Life", undated (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Gaps in Doctor-Patient Communication," by Ethel K. Gozzi, Marie J. Morris and Barbara M. Korsch; in "American Journal of Nursing," March, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Historian's Nightmare," by Henry F. Pringle; in "This Week," May 2, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - Illustrations: Articles:"How To Play the Consumer Game," author unidentified; in "American Cyanamid Magazine", undated (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "I'll Take 1951!," by Morton M. Hunt; in "This Week," December 31, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - Illustrations: Articles: Incomplete, untitled article about underclothes through the ages, author unidentified; in "Collier's Magazine," December 8, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Indoctrination of the New Physician," by K. Miller; in "Johnson and Johnson Profiles," Spring, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Intimate Views of TV Interviewers," by Abner Dean; source unidentified, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Intransigent Patient," author unidentified; in "American Journal of Nursing," October, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Life Among the Pioneers," by H. Allen Smith; in "Saturday Evening Post", undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Look Who's Looking At TV!," by Abner Dean; in "Pageant," September, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Make Up Your Mind, Uncle Sam," by George Soloveytchik; In "This Week," July 24, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Master Politician," by Ernest Haveman; in "Life", undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Memorable Wildfowling Days," by Dan Holland; in "Elks Magazine", undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Moral for March 15: You Can't Win," by Ernest Haveman; in "Life," March 6, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "1976: The Year We Lost Our Independence," by Robert B. Taylor, M.D.; in "Medical Economics," November 22, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Nurse Clinicians in Industry," by Josephine A. Cipolla and Gilbert H. Collings; in "American Journal of Nursing," August, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Nurse Manpower," by Eugene Levine; in "American Journal of Nursing," February, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Off With Her Head! Off--!," by Kathryn Halene Knicely; in "American Journal of Nursing," December, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "One Damn Foot After Another;" in "Venture", undated (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Other End of the Stethoscope," by Michael O'Donnell, M.D.; in "Family Health Preview Issue", undated (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Physicians Can Manage Realty to Gain Real Tax Relief," author unidentified; in "Medical World News," May 14, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Psychopates," by Abner Dean; in "Pageant," May, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "A Rationale For Assignments," by Marjorie Ramphal; in "American Journal of Nursing," August, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Role Bargaining For Working Wives," by Virginia S. Cleland; in "American Journal of Nursing", undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Run That Rattled," in "The Flying Red Horse Magazine, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Shape of Man To Come," by Sir Julian Huxley; in "Medical World News," January 17, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Short-Short Story of Mankind," by John Steinbeck in "Playboy", undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Speaking of Pictures…," author unidentified; in "Life", undated (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Strange World of 1984" author unidentified; in "Life," July 16, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Switch Off, Tune In, Turn On," by Betty L. Cuthbert; in "American Journal of Nursing," June, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Three Factors That Affect Practice: Communications, Assignments, Attitudes," by Charlotte Theis and Helen Harrington; in "American Journal of Nursing" July, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "The Two Languages of Nursing and Medicine," by Joan E. Lynaugh and Barbara Bates; in "American Journal of Nursing," January, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Uncertain Hero," by Louis Lyndon; in "Woman's Home Companion," November, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "What Have I Learned From Men?," by Michael Drury; in "Woman's Home Companion," May, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "What To Do About Thirst," by Mary Fenton; in "American Journal of Nursing," May, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "What You Don't Know About Our Presidents," by George Stimpson; in "Collier's" Magazine, March 8, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Where Does This Go?," by Parke Cummings; in "Collier's" Magazine, May 31, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Wild, Wild Pheasant," by Ted Trueblood; in "Elks Magazine", undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Illustrations: Articles: "Will Germs Strike Back?," by Hilary Koprowski, M.D.; in "Medical World News," January 31, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Illustrations: Books: "Cave Drawings For The Future"; camera-ready paste-ups, undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Illustrations: Books: "Come As You Are"; rough drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Illustrations: Books: "Not Far From The Jungle"; rough drawings and verses, incomplete, undated (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Illustrations: Books: "The Relations Explosion," by William L. Safire; tear-sheets, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Illustrations: Brochures:"Culbertson on Contract," by Horace A. Quimby, undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Illustrations: Brochures: "+5," by Dick Holbrook, Abner Dean, Frank McCord and Bob Baumrucker, for the Class of 1931 Reunion, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Illustrations: Brochures: "The Things We Know That Are Not So," by Fred G. Clark and Richard Stanton Rimanoczy, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean: "The Hand-Off Play"; in "Esquire", undated (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean:"Loose Tongues"; in "Esquire", undated (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean: "Pipefuls of Personality"; in "Esquire," March, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean: "Psychopates"; in "Look", undated (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean: "A Salute To The Four Seasons," with Ogden Nash; in "Esquire," August, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Cartoon features by Abner Dean: "When Is A Dream Car?"; in "Ladies Home Journal", undated (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Column entitled ...Every Other Friday, author unidentified; in "Medical World News", undated (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Magazine Work: "College Humor"; cartoons, caricatures, drawings, 1932-1933 (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Magazine Work: "Common Sense"; drawings, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Magazine Work: "Cosmopolitan"; cartoon, undated (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Magazine Work: "Esquire"; cartoons, 1937-1939 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Magazine Work: "Fiction Parade"; cartoon, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Magazine Work: "Flair"; cartoons, final issue, undated (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Magazine Work: "Life"; photostats of drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 100)
    - Magazine Work: "Modern Youth"; misc. drawings, undated (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - Magazine Work: "Movie Classic"; cartoon, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - Magazine Work: "Newsweek"; cartoons, 1959-1966 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - Magazine Work: "Redbook"; cartoon, undated (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - Magazine Work: "Screenland"; caricatures, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - Magazine Work: "This Week"; cartoons, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    - Magazine Work: "University"; mastheads, 1933 (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - Magazine Work: "Woman's Home Companion"; cartoons, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Menu: Reunion of Executives Dinner, Standard Oil Co., New Jersey, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Misc. illustrations from "American Journal of Nursing", undated (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - Hand-colored woodblock print (possible illustration for a wine article), undated (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Hand-colored woodblock print (possible illustration for a wine article), undated undated (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Hand-colored woodblock print (possible illustration for a wine article), undated (Box 3, Folder 113)